Register to the Paul Hindemith Collection
Yale University Music Library
- MATERIAL RELATING TO HINDEMITH'S COMPOSITIONS, 1913-1993; Series I; 3.5' (8 boxes)
  - When Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom'd, A Requiem for Those We Love, for mezzo-soprano and baritone solo, mixed chorus and orchestra, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 185)
    - 1952 review in Hamburg newspaper
    - Review by H. Schneiber Vienna 1959
    - Documentation of Gertrud Hindemith's gift of score to Yale: Yale Daily News 1964, New York Herald Tribune 1964
    - Publicity release from Yale 1964
    - Photo of replica of Lincoln's parlor
    - R. Shaw: Newsletter to Friends of Atlanta Symphony 1971
    - Reel 2/1-162
  - Symphonia Serena for orchestra, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 186)
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1946-47
    - N. del Mar: notes for Angel recording
    - Photocopy of printed score
    - Programs: Yale 1973, 1978, 1979
    - Reviews: P. G. Davis New York Times 1979; B. Zakariasen New York Daily News 1979; D. L. Schank New Haven Register 1979; Notes by J. Mauceri for same
    - C. Rollason, H. Goff, D. Tabbat: student papers
  - Apparebit repentina dies, for mixed chorus, 4 horns, 2 trumpets, 3 trombones, tuba, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - Schedule of premiere and program with typewritten translation of medieval text by John Peter Elder, Harvard University with his corrections
    - Programs: New York 1947 & 1961, Illinois 1951, Yale 1985 & 1993, New Haven Chorale 1989
  - Concerto for clarinet and orchestra, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - Holograph score (Box 31, Folder 433)
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker 1947, Paul Hindemith -H. Strecker 1947, Gertrud Hindemith-W. Strecker 1950, Paul Hindemith -K. Bauer 1950, Gertrud Hindemith-W. Strecker 1950, Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox 1952, Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1950, Gertrud Hindemith-E. Ormandy 1953; E. Simon-Paul Hindemith 1941, 6 letters
    - Billboard cover 25 Oct 1947
    - Letters: L. Noss-Billboard
    - V. Persichetti: review in The Musical Quarterly 1951
    - Article on B. Goodman in US News & World Report 14 August 1978
    - D. Neumeyer: introduction to III, 7
    - Reel 2/380-418
  - Sonata for violoncello and piano, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - N. Broder: notes for RCA recording
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1948
  - Suite französischer Tänze for small orchestra, arranged by Paul Hindemith from works by C. Gervaise and E. du Tertre, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 190)
  - I. Das Marienleben, revised - complete version, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - List of sketches compiled by D. Neumeyer 1975 with notice of his paper given at American Musicological Society 21 October 1978
    - Letter excerpts: Gertrud Hindemith-W. Strecker 1936, Paul Hindemith -E. Voigt 1941, -H. Fromm 1941, -W. Strecker 1941, -B. Knollenberg 1942, -E. Voigt 1942, -E. Voigt 1942, -K. Bauer 1945, -W. Strecker 1945, -W. Strecker 1946
    - Paul Hindemith journal note 1948
    - Two versions of dynamic and expressive graph prepared by Paul Hindemith but not in his hand, photocopy includes meter relationships
    - Translated foreword by A. Mendel from premiere program 23 January 1949 with sections IV and VI by L. Noss
    - Summary of foreword by L. Noss
    - A. Briner: Exkurs from biography
    - H. Schilling: article on Passacaglia Themes in Melos 1956
    - D. Reinker: student paper
  - II. Das Marienleben, revised, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Translations /programs: 23 January 1949 premiere in New York
    - Photocopy of R. G. L. Barrett: translation of Rilke text, p.15-18, which seems to be from revised publication
    - 1965 program by H. Boatwright with different translation
    - R. Ericson: review of New York concert 1967
    - 1975 program at Yale with same H. Boatwright translations
    - Photocopy various versions of songs in sketch and final forms
  - III. Das Marienleben, revised - songs with orchestral accompaniment, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Program of premiere - four songs with orchestra 24 June 1956 Nürnberg and brochure from city
    - Boston Symphony Orchestra notes for first 3 songs 1956
    - Program New York premiere of six songs with orchestra 1979 (see Symphonia Serena Box 6, Folder 186 same concert), copies of publicity release
  - Septett für Blasinstrumente, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - Note from interview with Paul Hindemith (no date)
    - Letter excerpt: Gertrud Hindemith-W & L. Strecker 1953
    - Programs: 1972, 1973, 1976, 1981
    - C. Fels: student paper
  - Concerto for horn and orchestra without brass, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - Holograph score (Box 31, Folder 434)
    - N. del Mar: notes for Angel recording
    - Notes from Minnesota Orchestra 1981
    - Reviews: H. Reich of premiere in Badische Zeitung 1950; K. Wagner in Musica 4 1950; H. Hagen in Neue Zeitung Munich 1950; J. Lübbers in Die Welt Hamburg 1950; G. Görgen's in Musik im Unterricht 1950
    - D. Neumeyer: introduction to III, 7
  - Concerto for woodwinds, harp, and orchestra, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - Comments from R. H. Hagan for recording (?)
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker 1949, Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1949
    - L. Noss: preface and critical notes to III, 7
    - Program from premiere 1949
    - Reviews: H. Cowell in The Musical Quarterly; V. Thomson in New York Herald Tribune; N. Strauss in New York Times
    - Reviews of European premiere 1950: K. Wagner in Musica 4; H. Reich in Badische Zeitung; H. Hagen in Neue Zeitung Munich; J. Lübbers in Die Welt Hamburg; G. Görgen in Musik im Unterricht
    - Review of published score in Zeitschrift für Musik 1952
    - Reviews: C. Durgin in Musical America 1955; F. Hruby in Musical America 1961; G. H. in Die Abendzeitung Munich 1960; J. Kaiser in Süddeutsche Zeitung Munich 1960; K. Ganzer in Augsburger Allgemeine Zeitung 1960
    - R. H. Hagan: notes for Fantasy record
    - Program of Vienna Festival 1952
    - Photocopy of original reviews published in Germany
    - Notes from Boston Symphony Orchestra 1965
  - The Demon of the Gibbet for male chorus, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - L. Noss-A. Rubeli 1983 exchange
    - Photocopy of printed version & photocopy of holograph
  - Sonata for double bass and piano, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 198)
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker 1949, Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1949
    - H. R. review in Musica 4 1950
    - Yale program 1976
  - Concerto for trumpet and bassoon with string orchestra, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 199)
    - Holograph score (Box 32, Folder 435)
    - Notes from Vienna Festival 1952 untranslated
    - L. Noss: preface and critical notes for III, 7
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker 1949, L. Noss-CT Academy of Arts and Sciences; E. Goodenough-Paul Hindemith 1948-49, notes from Academy archives
    - Reviews of Baden-Baden premiere 1951: H. L. M. in Badisches Tageblatt; E. Clement in Das Volk Freiburg; H. F. in Badische Zeitung
    - Photocopy of Südwestrundfunk broadcast notes and other German reviews
    - Photocopy of sketches + score and extracted solo parts by Paul Hindemith; piano reduction for rehearsal in another hand (see also oversize Box 43)
  - Birthday Canon for Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 200)
    - Ozalid and photocopy
    - Poem "In honor of Paul Hindemith" by Harold Rogers from Christian Science Monitor
  - Sinfonietta for symphony orchestra, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 201)
    - Note from A. Briner's biography
    - Reviews of European premiere 1950: G. Görgen in Musik im Unterricht; H. Hagen in Neue Zeitung Munich; H. Reich in Badische Zeitung
    - Ballet reviews 1975
  - CAL, the lad of Ohio's anniversary song. Verses by F. W. Bronson, editor of Yale Alumni Magazine, set to music by Paul Hindemith with pencil drawings of Carl Lohmann by Paul Hindemith., 1951 (Box 7, Folder 201)
    - Holograph score (Box 31, Folder 436)
    - see also Boxes 37-43
  - Symphony in B-flat for concert band, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 202)
    - Letters between R. Thurston-E. W. Allen to obtain manuscript for collection 1981
    - Letter excerpt: Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1951
    - R. Thurston's article in The Instrumentalist 1981
    - Publisher's flyer announcing forthcoming publication with reviews of premiere in Washington DC
    - R. F. Goldman: review in The Musical Quarterly 1958
    - Notice of recording by Universityof Michigan band
    - Notice and programs from Lewis & Clark College 1970, Penn State 1973, Yale 1975 & 1981
  - Symphonie, Die Harmonie der Welt, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 203)
    - Notes by Paul Hindemith from Minneapolis premiere 1953
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-B. Simonds 1951, Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1952, Gertrud Hindemith-W. Strecker 1953
    - L. Noss: notes for 1979 Yale Philharmonia program
    - Willie Ruff: notes
    - Photocopy of notes from A Composer's World
    - Programs: New Haven & New York of Philharmonia 1979
    - Photocopy of New York reviews: B. Zakariasen in Daily News; P. G. Davis in New York Times; D. L. Schank in New Haven Register
    - K. H. Wörner: article in Melos 1955 with photocopy of original German
    - P. Hayworth: review in The London Times (?)
    - J. McC.: review in Records and Recordina 1971
  - Cardillac, revised, opera in four acts, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 204)
    - Notes from I. Kemp's monograph and A. Briner's biography
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1948, Paul Hindemith-B. Simonds 1948, Gertrud Hindemith-B. Simonds 1952, -K. Bauer 1952, -W. Strecker 1952
    - J. Marein: review in Die Zeit of German premiere 1953
    - Programs: Kassel 1958, Berlin 1977
    - Published libretto with translation
    - H. L. Schilling: "The Two Versions of the opera 'Cardillac'" in translation
    - Y. Liepa: student paper
  - Sonata for four horns, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 205)
    - Letter excerpt: Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker 1952
  - Ite angeli veloces for mezzo-soprano, contralto, tenor soli, mixed chorus, orchestra, band, audience on text by Paul Claudel, I and III based on Old Testament sources, 1953-55 (Box 7, Folder 206)
    - Notes from A. Briner's biography
    - K. H. Wörner: comments in Neue Zeitschrift für Musik 116, 1955 with photocopy of original including Paul Hindemith's introduction and Claudel's; also further partial translation of Wörner's article
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-O. Cox 1955, Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1957, Gertrud Hindemith-K. Bauer 1958
    - Programs: 1956, 1958 with copies of audience leaflet
  - Neues vom Tage, revised, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 207)
    - H. Strobel: comments in biography 1948
    - A. Briner: comments in 1971 biography
    - G. Skelton: comments in biography
    - I. Kemp: comments in monograph
    - Letter excerpt: Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1954
    - Program of Naples premiere 1954
    - Program from Sante Fe 1961
    - D. Allanbrook: review in New Mexican 1961
    - Program: Manhattan School 1979 with Reviews: A. Porter in New Yorker; A. Rich in New York; J. Diether in East Side Express; R. Ericson in New York Times; M. Bernheimer of Santa Fe in Los Angeles Times 1981; D. Henahan of same in New York Times
    - Translation of 1953 libretto revision
  - Sonata for tuba and piano, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 208)
    - Yale programs: 1972, 1979
    - A. Chipman: review in New Haven Register of Columbia recording 1976
  - Two Songs for soprano/tenor and piano on texts by Oscar Cox, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 209)
    - 1. Image
    - 2. Beauty touch me
    - Holograph scores (Box 31, Folder 437)
    - Letter excerpts: Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox 1954, Paul Hindemith-O. Cox 1954-55
    - Proof copy of ad from Germany
  - I. Die Harmonie der Welt, opera in five acts, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 210)
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker 1939, Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker 1947, Gertrud Hindemith-K. Bauer 1956, Paul Hindemith-O. Cox 1956, Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss 1956, Gertrud Hindemith-G & R. Donovan 1956, Paul Hindemith-O. Cox, Gertrud Hindemith-L & O. Cox, Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss, Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1957, Paul Hindemith-O. Cox 1957, Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1957, Paul Hindemith-O. Cox 1957, Gertrud Hindemith-M & B. Cannon
    - 1974 Harvard College Observatory-R. Kirkpatrick re: naming a moon crater for Paul Hindemith
    - R. Huch: article from Der grosse Krieg in Deutschland II, 1920 [The Thirty Years' War]
    - A. Briner: Exkurs from biography
    - Premiere program: W. Gerstenberg's article; W. Gerlach: Kepler's "Harmonice mundi;" F. Hammer on life of Kepler; M. Stephan's article
    - R. Reinhold: article in 1972 New York Times on Kepler's 400th anniversary
    - L. Sträter: article reprinted from Frankfurter Neue Presse 1971 in The German Tribune 1972
    - d'Angelo: bibliography and correspondence
  - II. Die Harmonie der Welt, opera libretti, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 211)
    - German published version
    - Translation by J. d'Angelo 1977 "follows the vocal lines"
    - Free translation by L. Noss, undated
    - Paul Hindemith's original typescript with corrections, additions, and autograph
  - III. Die Harmonie der Welt, opera, reviews of premiere, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 212)
    - English synopsis from Munich
    - Booklet published by Bavarian Academy of Arts in honor of the premiere 1957
    - Program from Munich Festival with special insert for Paul Hindemith opera
    - K. H. Ruppel: review in Süddeutsche Zeitung Munich with Münchener Merkur translation
    - Reviews: G. L. Mayer in American Record Guide; Newsweek; N. Goodwin in New York Herald Tribune; The London Times, also interview after the premiere; Time; E. Helm in New York Times
    - Photos from London Sunday Times
    - Program: 1966 Gelsenkirchen (abridged version) plus article in advance of performance from Gelsenkirchen newspaper
  - Die Harmonie der Welt, a recorded realization for the ear by Willie Ruff and John Rodgers, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - Photocopies of article in Kayhan International, Tehran, Iran 1977
    - Yale Weekly Bulletin 14 Nov 1977 article
    - CT Academy of Arts & Sciences poster 1977
    - Invitation to the Club 1978
    - J. Blanksteen/H. Schonberg articles in New York Times 24 Apr 1979
  - Oktett for clarinet, bassoon, horn, violin, 2 violas, violoncello, double bass, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - P. Evans: notes for London recording
    - K. H. Wörner: analysis in Melos 25, 1958 with photocopy of original
    - H. Taubman: review New York Times 1959
    - Flyers and programs from Town Hall concert, press release by BMI with reprints of reviews by P. H. Lang in New York Herald Tribune, L. Biancolli in New York World Telegram, M. Kastendieck in New York Journal American, J. Johnson in New York Post
    - Program from Norfolk CT 1972
    - M. Peterson: review of Berlin Philharmonic Octet in Los Angeles Times 1976
  - Zwölf Madrigale for SSATB unaccompanied 1. Mitwelt 2. Eines Narren 3. Tauch deine 4. Trink aus! 5. An eine Tote 6. Frühling 7. An einem Schmetterling 8. Judaskuss 9. Magisches Rezept 10. Es bleibt wohn 11. Kraft fand 12. Du Zweifel, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Notes from A. Rubeli's monograph with translations of Nos. 6-11-12
    - Card from Hedi Straumann, to whom the Madrigals are dedicated, to O & L. Noss 1954
    - W. Kirsch: article in Jahrbuch VII/78
    - New York premiere (of 6) 1959: Flyer announcing concert; Town Hall program with text inserts in German and English
    - BMI press kit with photocopy reviews: P. H. Lang in New York; Herald Tribune, H. Taubman in New York Times; L. Biancolli in New York World Telegra; M. Kastendieck in New York Journal American; H. Johnson in New York Post; two articles by E. Salzman in New York Times and J. Harrison in New York Herald Tribune
    - Original reviews: H. Taubman New York Times; P. H. Lang in New York Herald Tribune
    - New York Times & New York Herald Tribune articles re: Music Critics Circle award to Madrigals, two days after performance
  - Pittsburgh Symphony for orchestra, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - A. Briner's comments from his biography
    - Letter excerpts: Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox 1958, Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1958, Paul Hindemith-O. Cox 1958
    - Correspondence re: commissioning - L. Noss-S. Rosen 1980, K. Butera-L. Noss 1980, L. Noss-K. Butera 1980, L. Noss-J. Edwards 1980 + excerpts from minutes of Pittsburgh Symphony Society Board of Directors
    - Review of premiere: D. Steinfirst in Pittsburgh Post-Gazette 1959; another performance later that year
    - F. Dorian: review in The Musical Quarterly 1959
    - Ad from Oslo 1959
    - A. Briner: article in Melos 1959 + original German
    - Photocopy of Paul Hindemith's notes from original program
    - G. Metz: letters requesting information for complete edition
  - Max Reger: Psalm 100 revised edition by Paul Hindemith, published by Edition Peters, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Published version, autographed
  - Marsch über den alten "Schweizerton" für Orchester, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - Festprogramm of the 500th anniversary celebration of the University of Basel
  - I. The Long Christmas Dinner, opera in one act; libretto by Thornton Wilder, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - A. Briner's comments in biography
    - W. Kirsch: commentary in Jahrbuch II/72
    - I. Kemp's comments in his monograph
    - N. J. Schneider: article on the correspondence between Paul Hindemith and Wilder in Jahrbuch 82/XI
    - Paper napkin sent to Wilder by Paul Hindemith in 1960 with comments
    - Letter excerpts: 1960 Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss, I. Wilder-O. Noss, 1961 Paul Hindemith-O. Cox, Gertrud Hindemith-I. Wilder, Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss, 1962, Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox, Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss, Gertrud Hindemith-L. Noss, Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox, Gertrud Hindemith-T. Wilder, Gertrud Hindemith-L. Noss
  - II. The Long Chistmas Dinner, opera, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - Program from world premiere in Mannheim 1961
    - Program from Rome 1961-62 season
    - Brochure by Schott/AMP with excerpts from five reviews of Juilliard performance
    - American premiere at Juilliard 13 March 1963 with program of four performances (2 copies)
    - P. H. Lang: review in New York Herald Tribune 14 April
    - I. Kolodin(?): review in Saturday Review 30 March
    - Program of Washington performance 17 March
    - Trimmed photos of Juilliard production from Juilliard News Review April 1963
    - English libretto and English-German libretto
    - Three copies of English-German libretto inscribed or autographed by Paul Hindemith
    - Collection of one-act plays by T. Wilder
    - Alexandra Ven-Ling Yu-T. Wilder correspondence 1970 re: Community Opera production 1969, with A. Yu-L. Noss exchanges re: gift to collection
    - Juilliard Review Annual 1962-63 with complete libretto and photos of opera and Der Dämon and Hérodiade performed with it
  - Mainzer Umzug for soprano, tenor, baritone, narrators, mixed chorus, and full orchestra, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - Time magazine article 1 February 1963
    - Letter excerpt: Paul Hindemith-O. Cox 1962
  - Concerto for organ and orchestra, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - Letter excerpt: Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss 1962
    - Program from world premiere in New York 25 April 1963, plus separate pages from same
    - Review: R. Parmenter in New York Times
    - W. Kirsch: comments in Jahrbuch II/72
    - W. Öhlmann: review in Der Taggespiel 1965
    - M. R.: review in Die Welt (Berlin) 1965
    - Photocopy of 1975 letter from A. Heiller to V. de Tar re: his performance of work
    - Program: Yale 1984
  - Mass for mixed chorus a cappella, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - A. Briner's notes from biography
    - Letter excerpt: Gertrud Hindemith-O & L. Noss 1964
    - A. Rubeli's comments from monograph
    - W. Kirsch: comments in Jahrbuch II/72
    - A. Beaujean: review of East German recording in Jahrbuch IV/74
    - D. Johns: review of Vienna 1963 performance in The Musical Quarterly April 1964 (incomplete)
    - Press release of 1964 weekend at Yale with program of St. Thomas More performance
    - Program of R. Vikstrom's performance 1966 Chicago
    - Yale Program of 1973 Kyrie & Gloria performances
- SPEECHES, WRITINGS, AND TEACHING MATERIALS, 1927-1965; Series II; .75' (2 boxes)
  Speeches, writings, and teaching materials are housed in Boxes 910. They contain, among other items, versions of "The Craft of Musical Composition, Parts I-II-III-IV," materials and proofs for "Traditional Harmony, Parts I-II," "Elementary Training for Musicians," "The Composer's World," autographed copies of the lecture on J. S. Bach in English and German, and other writings. Some additional materials may be found in oversize Box 43.
  - Equal Temperament: 6 to 53 tones to the octave, 1940s (Box 9, Folder 224)
    - 4 photocopies
    - Ditto copy of "The seventh overtone as a constituent part of an interval system with unlimited possibilities of transposition"
    - Ditto copy of "Tones and Intervals of the Pythagorean and the Natural Systems, and of 12-tone Equal Temperament, Together with the Intervals of the Overtone Series between Tones 1 and 17;" Hierarchy of the Scale and scale of values
  - The Craft of Musical Composition, 1937-39 (Box 9, Folder 225)
    (see also Box 14, Folders 277-281)
    - Photocopy of part of German edition 1937, omitted in English 1942
    - Chronology of Vol. I and Vol. II
    - References to Vol. I and II in letters
    - R. Hasse: Paul Hindemith's Sources of Harmonic Theory - correspondence with H. Kayser 1973
    - P. Cahn: article in Jahrbuch I/71
    - B. Zwink: notes from Ph. D dissertation
    - J. Harley: article in The Musical Times 1954
    - W. Öhlmann: "A half century: Chronicle and Appraisal" in Musica 4
    - A. Rubeli: comments from his monograph
    - K. S|rensen [ie K. Stone]: review in Dansk Musiktidsskrift 12, 1937 with English translation by Else Stone, 1994
    - V. Thomson: review of I-II New York Herald Tribune 1942
    - G. Nestler: "Betonungsrhythmik und musicalische Form..." Melos 18, 1951
    - B. Billeter: "Can the 'Craft' be used for analysis?" Jahrbuch II/72
    - G. Lam: proposal for electronic demonstration of overtone and combination-tone theories 1964
    - Letter excerpt: Paul Hindemith-Gertrud Hindemith 1939
    - A. Briner: article in Journal of Music Theory 1961
    - B. Heiden: article for Modern Music 1941, reprinted by AMP
    - D. Henahan: "Music of the Spheres" New York Times 1978
  - The Craft of Musical Composition: Plan for revision of Part II - 2-part Writing, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - Original and 2 copies plus some historical examples
  - A Concentrated Course in Traditional Harmony, 1942-43 (Box 9, Folder 227)
    - Flyer from AMP
    - Letter excerpts: 1942 Paul Hindemith-E. Voigt, 1946 -W. Strecker, 1947 -W. Strecker
    - Pre-publication copy used in class 1941-42
  - Elementary Training for Musicians, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 228)
    (see also typescript version with all musical examples in oversize Box 43)
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1944, 1945, Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker 1945, 1946, 1947
  - Clef Transposition Book: Exercises for Advanced Students - 3 copies, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 229)
    (see also oversize Box 43)
  - A Concentrated Course in Traditional Harmony, Part II, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 230)
    - Holograph manuscript (see oversize Box 43)
    - Letter excerpts: Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer 1948, Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker 1949
    - Pre-publication copies of Vocal Fugue, Clarinet Sonatina
    - (see also holograph materials in Box 31, Folder 439 and German version in oversize Box 43)
  - The Craft of Musical Composition, Part III: 3-Part Writing, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 231)